Guide to the John S. Van E. Kohn Edna St. Vincent Millay Collection, 1917-1976
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
John S. Van E. Kohn Edna St. Vincent Millay Collection
1917-1976
Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950
0.8 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Materials collected by John S. Van E. Kohn, bibliophile and co-founder of the Seven Gables Bookshop in New York City. Includes manuscripts, correspondence, clippings, sheet music, miscellaneous printed material, photographs and notes compiled by Kohn about Millay's publication and his collection. The correspondence includes 8 letters to Frank Crowinshield, managing editor of Vanity Fair, and Karl Yost, a Millay bibliographer.
Biographical Note
See the biographical note in the
Guide to the Edna St.Vincent Millay Papers
.
Scope and Content Note
Materials collected by John S. Van E. Kohn, bibliophile and co-founder of the Seven Gables Bookshop in New York City. Includes manuscripts, correspondence, clippings, sheet music, miscellaneous printed material, photographs and notes compiled by Kohn about Millay's publication and his collection.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Edna St.Vincent Millay Papers
Anne Gardner Edna St. Vincent Millay Collection
Subject Headings
Names:
Crowninshield, Frank, 1872-1947; Boissevain, Eugen, -1949; Yost, Karl, 1911-
Subjects:
American literature--Women authors; Women poets
Document Types:
Correspondence; Photographs; Poems; Printed ephemera; Sheet music
VCL Categories:
Literature and Writing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, March 2007. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, January 2024.
Acquisition Information
Received from Lippincott Books, 1998.
Series List
- Series I. Manuscripts, 1928, undated
- Series II. Correspondence, 1920-1975
- Series III. Publications, 1917-1976
- Series IV. Sheet Music, 1928-1936
- Series V. Photographs, circa 1926-1928, undated
- Series VI. Miscellaneous Notes of John S. Van E. Kohn, 1959-1969, undated
Container List
- Series I. Manuscripts
  - "Not That It Matters" — Early draft later published in The Buck in the Snow, undated; (MS 1 p.) (Folder 1.1)
  - Sheet of music from the closing scene of Act III of The King's Henchman, signed by Deems Taylor, 6 Feb 1928; (MS 1 p.) (Folder 3.1)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Letters from Millay
    - Millay to Franklin P. Adams, 11 Aug [1928?]; (1 letter) (Folder 1.2)
    - Millay to Frank Crowninshield, 1921-1947; (8 letters) (Folder 1.3)
    - Millay to Alan Ross Macdougall, 14 Sep 1920; (1 letter) (Folder 1.4)
  - Letters from Others
    - Basler, Roy P. to John S. Van E. Kohn — Includes a 1968 press release and copy of the announcement in the October 1968 Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress, 7 Mar 1972 (Folder 1.5)
    - Boissevain, Eugene — correspondence with John Black, Cutis Page, Kimball Flaccushas, J Paget-Fredericks, 1935-1941; (10 letters — 31 Aug 1931 letter to Kimball Flaccus has a postscript by Millay) (Folder 1.6)
    - Bynner, Witter to Kimball Flaccus, 31 Jan 1957; (1 letter) (Folder 1.7)
    - Chriswick Book Shop to John S. Van E. Kohn, 5 June 1974, 30 Dec 1975; (2 letters) (Folder 1.8)
    - Collamore, H. B. to Allan Ross Macdougall, 1951; (2 letters) (Folder 1.9)
    - Dillion, George to Amy Bonner, 1935; (1 photocopied letter) (Folder 1.10)
    - Ellis, Norma Millay to John Kohn, 6 Oct 1962, 19 Jan 1965; (2 letters) (Folder 1.11)
    - Hoag, Paul F. to John S. Van E. Kohn, 10 Mar 1969; (1 letter) (Folder 1.12)
    - Kennerley, Mitchell to the editor of Publisher's Weekly, 17 May 1937; (1 letter) (Folder 1.13)
    - Kohn, John S. Van E. to Don, 1967; (1 letter) (Folder 1.14)
    - Macdougall, Allan Ross correspondence with Susan Glaspell and H. B. Collamore, 29 Oct 1928, 1951; (4 letters) (Folder 1.15)
    - Plum, Dorothy A to John S. Van E. Kohn, 1959, 1964; (2 letters) (Folder 1.16)
    - Reese, L. W. to Friend, 16 Mar 1925; (1 letter) (Folder 1.17)
    - Rushmore, Arthur W. to John S. Van E. Kohn, 1935; (1 letter) (Folder 1.18)
    - Yost, Karl to John S. Van Kohn, 1933–1938, 1961; (19 letters) (Folder 1.19)
- Series III. Publications
  - Advertisements
    - The King's Henchman — Paper clipping advertising a complete set of five librettos for sale, undated (Folder 1.20)
    - Fatal Interview — by Harper & Brothers, undated (Folder 1.21)
    - Fatal Interview — Booklet of advertisements for new books being published by Harper Books, Spring 1931 (Folder 1.22)
    - No Fit Place for a Child to Play — The Jean Cocteau Theatre, 1973 (Folder 1.23)
  - Articles
    - "The Development of the Social Consciousness of Edna St. Vincent Millay as manifested in her poetry,", 1943 (Folder 1.24)
    - "Edna Millay Has No Sweet Song Left for a World Where Gun is the Law,", 19 Apr 1939 (Folder 1.25)
    - "Edna St. Vincent Millay's Afterthoughts on the Translation of Baudelaire,", 1976 (Folder 1.26)
    - "The Millay Biography – A Book for Mrs. Bowen,", June 1957 (Folder 1.27)
    - "Some Undergraduate Printings of Edna St. Vincent Millay,", 30 Nov 1940 (Folder 1.28)
    - "Vincent at Steepletop,", Feb 1957 (Folder 1.29)
    - "Vincent at Vassar," reprinted from the May 1951 Vassar Alumnae Magazine with added pictures by Blanche Ferry Hooker, Nov 1951 (Folder 1.30)
    - Letter to the editor of Vassar Alumnae Magazine, by Charlotte Babock Sills, Dec 1960 (Folder 1.31)
    - "Youth and Wings: Edna St. Vincent Millay: Singer," by Carl Van Doren, undated (Folder 1.32)
  - Playbills
    - Brooklyn Academy of Music playbills for Millay's reading of her poetry during the 1933-1934 season, circa 1933; (2 items) (Folder 1.33)
    - No Fit Place for a Child to Play — Performance schedule for The Jean Cocteau Theatre, November 1973 (Folder 1.34)
    - The Jean Cocteau Theatre, 7 Sep - 16 Dec 1973; (1 item) (Folder 1.35)
  - Poems by Millay
    - "The Bean-stalk," Poetry, A Magazine of Verse, May 1920 (Folder 2.1)
    - "Christmas Canticle," What's New?, 1950 (Folder 3.2)
    - "Christmas Card," 4 line unpublished poem, includes handwritten note quoting a letter by A. W. Rushmore about the Christmas card, Oct 1935, undated; (2 items) (Folder 2.2)
    - "God's World" broadsides, both Series 1, No. 2, from Renascence And Other Poems, 1938; (2 items) (Folder 2.3)
    - The Pamphlet Poets: Edna St. Vincent Millay, 1927 (Folder 2.4)
    - "Song of a Second April,", circa 1930 (Folder 2.5)
    - "There Are No Islands Any More, lines written in passion and in deep concern for England, France and My own country,", undated (Folder 3.3)
    - "Thou art not lovelier than lilacs – no,", 31 Oct 1935 (Folder 2.6)
  - Miscellaneous Publications by Millay
    - "Commencement; After Vassar---What?,", 1917 (Folder 2.7)
    - The King's Henchman, 1927; (7 items) (Folder 2.8)
    - "The Little Boy Next Door,", Apr 1941 (Folder 2.9)
- Series IV. Sheet Music
  - "Elaine," music by Constance Mills Herreshoff, 1931 (Folder 2.10)
  - "The Little Tavern," music by Ruth Wright Vanderlip, 1929 (Folder 2.11)
  - "My Candle (It Gives a Lovely Light)," music by Annabel Morris Buchanan, 1928 (Folder 2.12)
  - "Tavern," music by Michael Mullinar, 1929 (Folder 2.13)
  - "Vanished Summer," music by Edward Harris, 1936 (Folder 2.14)
- Series V. Photographs
  - Photographs of Millay
    - Snapshot at home at Steepletop, undated (Folder 2.15)
    - Portrait, undated (Folder 2.16)
  - Photographs of Millay and Others
    - Millay with her Aunt Susie Ricker, circa 1926 (Folder 2.17)
  - Photographs of the Ricker Family
    - Portrait of Sue Ricker, 1928 (Folder 2.18)
    - Portrait of Randolph J. Ricker, undated (Folder 2.19)
    - Snapshot of Aunt Susie and Norma, undated (Folder 2.20)
    - Snapshots of the Rickers and photographs of Sue Ricker's home and garden, Portland, Maine, undated; (6 items) (Folder 2.21)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous Notes of John S. Van E. Kohn
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1959, 1965, 1969, undated; (10 items) (Folder 2.22)